Zach Weinberg

FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER

Profile

Full-stack software engineer with a focus on JavaScript and TypeScript. Wide array of experience across both frontend and backend using different libraries and frameworks. Over 4 years of experience with React and even more with backend Node.js tech.

Employment History

Software Engineer, Opendoor

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Core team member who helped guide the engineering migration to Opendoor via acquisition (see below)
- Building a new financing experience for Opendoor's home buyers
- Contributing to a TypeScript REST-API that integrates with many third party services
- · Working across the web stack with Next.js and Firebase
- Helping the product team understand engineering blockers and requirements in order to move quickly

Full Stack Engineer, RedDoor, Remote

APRIL 2020 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Acquired by Opendoor
- Part of the core engineering team that helped build the future of the mortgage and real estate industry by empowering home buyers to find the best mortgage for their needs with the click of a few buttons
- Using React and Next.js for custom mortgage origination web tools
- Managed Google Cloud deploys along with a GitHub Actions workflow
- Worked on a TypeScript backend that used Firebase for database functionality and real-time features to support mobile apps
- Worked closely with product teams to plan sprints
- Wrote code to originate loans and guide customers through a great experience
- Maintained refinance and purchase loan logic that still helps customers become homeowners

Full Stack Web Developer, Cubepros, Boston, MA

JANUARY 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Designed, built and deployed numerous full stack JavaScript applications (MERN stack), some of which are now available on the QuickBooks Online app store
- Built and maintained company web infrastructure from scratch, including their website and tools to help accountants optimize their workflows
- Core technologies included Node.js, React, PostgreSQL and SCSS
- Built a tool that connects Slack users with their QuickBooks Online accounting data via webhooks and user initiated commands
- Collaborated with designers to turn static designs into working websites
- Worked on Wordpress websites (PHP)

Web Developer, Tapfood, Madison, NJ

Details

Boston, MA

zweinberg3@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

GitHub: zachweinberg

zachweinberg.com

Skills

TypeScript

Node.js

React

Next.js

Git and GitHub

JavaScript (ES6+)

Firebase

Unit Testing

SQL

CI/CD

Heroku

Vue

Google Cloud Platform

HTML & CSS

Languages

English

- Collaborated with core team to design a REST API that would support a food delivery service and implemented it using Node.js
- Built website frontend using React with a focus on simplicity and ease of use
- Migrated existing backend from Firebase to internal API with Postgresql
- Set up a bug alert pipeline, so bugs could easily be caught and fixed quickly
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting design elements that are also prevalent in the tapfood iOS app
- Designed complex backend routes such as getting distances by GPS coordinates and search queries
- Built Twilio and Stripe integrations from scratch

Web Developer, My Bus Home, Boston, MA

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

- Contract position
- Created a Node.js website with Express and EJS that helps college students schedule bus transportation home during school breaks
- Built an admin panel for company employees to log in and manage trip reservations
- Built a bulk email sending queue with AWS SQS and Sendgrid

Freelancer, Upwork

DECEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2020

 Helped clients from different backgrounds accomplish their web-related goals, most of which involved full-stack JavaScript

Education

B.S. Economics, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017